foreign
[Music]
mineral density screening may be a
billion dollar industry but only 15
percent of low trauma fractures are due
to osteoporosis in older women meaning
from a fall no more than from standing
height only 15 percent of fractures are
due to having low bone density between
the ages of 1680 hip fracture risk
increases 13-fold in men and women
whereas the age-related decline in bone
mineral density accounted for only a
two-fold increased risk so the
contribution of declining bone density
to the exponential increase in hip
fracture risk with age is relatively
small the vast majority of our
age-related rise in hip fracture risk
appears to have nothing to do with the
measured density of our bones so what's
the main contributor fall risk
without a fall even fragile Hips Don't
fracture Falls are the primary cause of
fractures including vertebral fractures
the disparity between men and women and
hip fracture rates is primarily not
because men have stronger bones but
because women fall more often doctors
just asking the simple question do you
have impaired balance can predict about
40 percent of all hip fractures more
than a bone scan diagnosis of
osteoporosis even a weak osteoprotic
bone is strong enough to survive normal
life activities without the excessive
loading that comes from a fall impact or
in the case of the spine bending with
your back to lift something rather than
your knees the Primacy of Falls and
Fracture risk explains the number of
apparent osteoporosis paradoxes for
example despite the fact that about 75
percent of your bone mass may be
determined by your genes the
heritability of bone fractures appears
negligible at older ages because the
propensity to fall is much less
inherited
it also explains the poor predictive
value of bone density screening for
fractures adding bone mineral density
measures to a hip fracture risk score
based just on age sex height weight the
use of a walking Aid and cigarette
smoking did little to improve its
predictive power
a provocative editorial published in the
Journal of internal medicine entitled
osteoporosis the emperor has no clothes
suggested that it would be safer and
more effective to focus on fall
prevention rather than pharmaceutical
intervention
even though only about five percent of
Falls result in a fracture Falls are
very common among the age due in part to
age-related muscle weakness and loss of
balance more than a third of those age
65 and older fall each year and after a
hip fracture fewer than 50 percent
regain their pre-fracture function in
terms of walking ability and
Independence what can we do to prevent
injurious Falls based on dozens of
randomized controlled trials the single
intervention most strongly associated
with a reduction in Fall rates
exercise so exercise doesn't just boost
bone density more importantly it also
reduces the number of Falls over time by
23 percent and then over followers by 15
so if you followed a thousand people
around age 75 for a year and 480 fell a
total of 850 times without exercise
adding exercise will be expected to
result in 72 fewer followers and 195
fewer Falls
Tai Chi appears to reduce Falls by 19
balance and functional exercise like sit
to stand may reduce Falls by 24 and
multiple exercises typically balance and
functional exercise plus strength
training May reduce Falls by 34 percent
the reduced Falls rate then translates
into fewer fractures a recent
meta-analysis found that exercise
interventions mostly using a combination
of resistance exercise to improve lower
limb muscle strength and balance
training cut fracture rates nearly in
half
one year long trial that combines
strength training with step and jumping
aerobics and focused on balance and
Agility resulted in 74 fewer fractures
over the five-year period after the
study ended furthermore more than 70
percent of the women in the combo
exercise group went those five years
without a single injurious fall compared
to less than half of those in the
control group
trials on hip protectors which cushion
us sideways fall on the hip with plastic
Shields or foam pads sewn into special
underwear are often plagued with poor
compliance Studies have not found them
to be useful for reducing hip fracture
race among those living at home but
trials in nursing homes are Residential
Care Facilities do show a small
reduction in Risk translating into about
11 fewer people out of a thousand
suffering hip fractures due to wearing
hip protection
there are also Common Sense measures one
can employ quality improvement trials
involving interventions like patient
education have shown a 10 reduction in
Fall rates of for example keep things
within reach so you don't need to use
step stools use non-slip mats in the
bath and shower add grab bars in the
bathroom keep floors clutter free remove
small throw rugs or use double-sided
tape to keep them from slipping and make
sure all staircases have handrails and
adequate lighting you could also avoid
taking walks during inclement weather
and for those who walk leashed dogs
consider choosing smaller breeds or
ensuring proper training to prevent them
from lunging otherwise the main ways to
prevent fractures may not have changed
much over the decades since the classic
paper entitled strategies for prevention
of osteoporosis and hip fracture the
main ways to prevent these fractures are
to stop smoking be active and eat well
[Music]
thank you
foreign